Daniel Shaw

Full Stack Developer | Web Developer

**** 07590841741

@ danielshaw71@gmail.com

https://github.com/Daniel Shaw98

London

PROJECTS

Niche

Currently designing and building an e-learning marketplace MVP.

- · Designing frontend and components with Figma.
- Creating backend with Ruby on Rails API using the MVC model and Active Model Serializer tool.
- · Using Webpacker and learning React.js to build the frontend.

Website Portfolio

Self-made portfolio website designed using Figma, and built with JavaScript, HTML and CSS

- Showcasing my projects, including Vloyal and Supper Club.
- · https://danielshaw.uk

Vloyal

VLoyal was created to turn paper loyalty cards into virtual loyalty cards storing them in one app, using a QR code scanner to add virtual stamps.

- · Acted as the project lead and project manager.
- · Managed all merges and resolved all conflicts in GitHub.
- Implemented the QR code scanning feature to the web app.
- · Worked on multiple animations using JavaScript.
- Used Figma and CSS to add styling throughout the web app.
- Presented and showcased the final product to 100+ people.

Supper Club

Designed, implemented and shipped to production a clone of Airbnb called 'Supper Club'. The web app enabled users to create and showcase their supper club events, as well as to discover and buy tickets to other supper clubs.

· Lead and managed this week-long project.

EXPERIENCE

Venue Finding

DesignMyNight

= 2022 - 2023

Demonstrated clear effective communication and consistent fast response times, operating as the intermediary between clients and venues. I converted 12 sales within 8 weeks. Attended multiple networking events, developing client management and networking skills.

Events Sales Manager

Fortem International

= 2022

Held a client-facing role researching and connecting with new businesses to build a portfolio of clients for global trade shows run by Fortem International. Developed skills in sales, business development and client relationship management.

Property & Land Agent

Ideal Land

= 2019 - 2021

Bought in £7M worth of property deals between 2020-2021. Managed the office and day to day business, including setting up and updating the website, and building the Company LinkedIn profile from 200 to 1,300 followers within a year. My responsibilities included;

- Leading searches for land and properties, monitoring and updating the databases.
- Drawing up contracts for deals including NDA's, Retention letters and Heads of Terms
- Building relationships with new and current clients, as well as networking with industry professionals.
- Arranging GDPR and AML training for the company and managing the continued use of these practices.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-shaw-ds98/

SUMMARY

Over the past year I have pursued my career ambition to become a Full Stack Developer. This began through Codecademy supplemented by Free Code Camp and YouTube. I joined the Le Wagon Web Development Course in October and graduated as a Full Stack Developer. I worked 2 jobs part-time throughout spring and summer to help fund the course, whilst continuing to learn to code/programming.

SKILLS

Web Application Development

Problem Solving Teamwork Organisation

Ruby Ruby On Rails JavaScript HTML

CSS SQL Git/Version Control Heroku

Figma GitHub Bootstrap

EDUCATION

Web Development

Le Wagon

並 2023

- 9-week full-time intensive web development bootcamp, accredited by BCS.
- Learned and used HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, SQL, Git, GitHub, Figma, Heroku and Ruby/Ruby on Rails
- Conceptual learning included OOP, MVC, APIs and Version Control.

Business Entrepreneurship

University of the West of England

= 2017 - 2018

- Completed year 1 achieving a 2.1.
- Received ILM: Level 3 Award in Leadership & Management.

A-Levels

Emanuel School

= 2014 - 2016

 Mathematics, Economics, Business Studies & Geography.

CERTIFICATION

Ruby, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Completed a certification course for Ruby, JavaScript, HTML and CSS provided by Codecademy.